Finding Aid for Dorothy Leonard Judd Papers, 1935-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dorothy Leonard Judd Papers 1935-1974
Judd, Dorothy Leonard.
9 linear feet
851707 Aa 2
Resident of Grand Rapids, Michigan, delegate to the Michigan Constitutional Convention (1961-1962), chairwoman of the Michigan State Advisory Committee to the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, and member of the Michigan Civil Service Commission. Correspondence and topical files relating to her public activities; also materials concerning her interest in site planning for a Kent County airport; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dorothy Judd (donor no. 5311 ) and came to the library in several accessions beginning in 1972.
The collection is open to research.
Dorothy Leonard Judd was a longtime civic leader and political activist from Grand Rapids, Michigan. A graduate of Grand Rapids Central High School and Vassar College, Mrs. Judd also studied for her masters degree at the University of Michigan under political science professor James K. Pollock. She taught American history and government at Grand Rapids Central High School from 1921 to 1924. During this period, she also became involved in the formation of the League of Women Voters. She was elected president of the state league organization in 1928 and headed the national league's Efficiency in Government committee in 1932-1934. She continued working with the league in various capacities until 1966.
Dorothy Judd's life was devoted to civic activity. During 1935-1936, she was a member of the Michigan State Civil Service Study Commission (chaired by professor Pollock). Three decades later, she would be a member of the Michigan State Civil Service Commission, 1963-1968, serving for two years as chairperson. During 1963-1964, Mrs. Judd won election as a delegate to the state constitutional convention serving on the civil rights committee. From her active interest in civil rights causes, Mrs. Judd was selected to be a member and chair of the Michigan State Advisory Committee to the United States Commission on Civil Rights in the period 1963-1966.
In Grand Rapids, Mrs. Judd was involved in the formation of Citizens Action, a group established in opposition to Mayor George Welch and party boss Frank McKay. Citizens Action led a movement to have the mayor recalled and fought for reform of the city's method of assessing property taxes. As a result of CA's action, Mayor Welch resigned from office in 1950
Mrs. Judd died February 1989.
Except for some personal and genealogical studies, the Judd papers have been arranged into series accumulated as a result of specific interests and activities. These series include Michigan State Advisory Committee to the United States Commission on Civil Rights; Michigan Civil Service Commission; Michigan Constitutional Convention; Kent County Airport Site Planning; and Grand Rapids Politics and Reform.
Subjects:
Airports.; Civil rights--Michigan.; Civil service.; Goebel, Paul Gordon, 1901-; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Judd, Dorothy Leonard.; Kent County (Mich.); McKay, Frank D., 1883-; Michigan. Civil Rights Commission.; Michigan. Civil Service Commission.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; United States Commission on Civil Rights. Michigan State Advisory Committee.; Welsh, George Wilson, 1883-1974.; Women--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Women in politics--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Politics and government--1961-1970.
Genre Terms:
Slides.
- Family/Personal
  - The Ancestors of Siegel Wright Judd by Dorothy Leonard Judd, 1980 (Box 1)
  - The Ancestors of Charles H. Leonard 1848-1927 by Dorothy Leonard Judd, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous and biographical (Box 1)
- Michigan State Advisory Committee to the United States Commission on Civil Rights 1963-1966
  - Introductory information (Box 1)
  - Federal manpower and training legislation and programs (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship practices
    - Interviews (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Related materials (Box 1)
    - Federal rules and regulations (Box 1)
  - Job training and appropriate placement of minority youth in Michigan (transcripts of testimony before the Committee) (Box 1)
  - Statement of Thomas Roumell, director of Michigan Employment Security commission regarding implementation of policy and procedure with respect to serving minority groups May 1, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Statements of Governor George Romney regarding manpower development and vocational training and related issues (Box 1)
  - Michigan Catholic Welfare Conference January 1964 (Box 1)
  - Lansing Employment Advisory Council 1958 (Box 1)
  - Detroit open hearing June 30, 1964
    - Transcript (Box 1)
    - Working papers, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Publications (Box 1)
    - Statistics (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Grand Rapids open hearing April 23, 1964
    - Working papers (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Mott Program of the Flint Board of Education (Box 1)
  - Supplementary transcripts re programs in Flint, Lansing, and Grand Rapids (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and other papers regarding publication of report March 1965-April 1966 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Committee report: Equal Opportunity in Job Training and Placement for Minority Youth in Michigan 1964
    - Draft December 1, 1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Draft April 1965 (Box 1)
    - Corrections, deletions and additions to first draft May 10, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Final findings and recommendations May 20, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Report on Employment of Nonwhite Youth draft January 1966 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding civil rights issues 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- Michigan Civil Service Commission
  - "Origins of the Michigan Merit System," 1935-1941 (Box 2)
  - Veterans preference policy in Michigan state government employment 1936-1944 (Box 2)
  - Amendment to legislation 1940 (Box 2)
  - Civil service and the Michigan Constitutional Convention 1961-1963, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Speeches evaluating civil service system 1954-1969 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Civil Service Commission v. James Hare, Secretary of State of Michigan et al
    - General (Box 2)
    - Contractual employment policy (Box 2)
    - History of the Hare case 1941-1969 (Box 2)
    - Evolution of term "Personal Services" (Box 2)
    - Public Interest aspect (Box 2)
    - Judicial Opinions (Box 2)
    - Court papers (Box 2)
    - Publicity (Box 2)
  - Political Activity
    - General (Box 2)
    - Legal aspects of 1962 committee report (Box 2)
    - H.R.2591 (legislation to broaden political activity permitted to civil service employees) 1965 (Box 2)
    - Resource material (Box 2)
  - Position of Civil Service Dept. in state government structure
    - General (Box 2)
    - Employee relations (Box 2)
    - Power to create or abolish exempt job classifications 1951-1970, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Civil Service Finance
    - Budget planning (Box 2)
    - Establishment of program budgeting (Box 2)
    - Decentralization of costs (Box 2)
  - Employee Relations Policy of the Michigan Civil Service Commission
    - Origin 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Policy development and evaluation 1966 (Box 2)
    - Zeidler Plan 1966-1969, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Evolution of policy in the 1970s (Box 2)
    - Public hearing conference with Michigan State Employees Union (Box 2)
    - Governors Committee on Public Employee Relations (Box 2)
    - George Romney public statements (Box 2)
    - Franklin K. DeWald public (MCCC director) statements (Box 2)
    - Relations with employee unions, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Text of speeches at Employee Relations Conference, Michigan State Employees Association April 23, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Definition of MCCC's scope of authority under the Michigan Constitution and state's employees relations policy, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Federal legislation, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Michigan legislation (Box 2)
    - Administrative procedures for resolution of disputes, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Dismissal of two Grand Rapids school teachers (Box 3)
    - Code of Fair Labor Practices (Box 3)
    - Statistics (Box 3)
    - Source materials, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Michigan government administrative reorganization 1965, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Relations between MCCC and the Governor's Office (Box 3)
  - Equal opportunity in state civil service
    - Studies on non-white employment 1964-1968 (Box 3)
    - Memoranda: "Racial Identification of Examination Applicants" (Box 3)
    - Statistics and other information 1963-1966 (Box 3)
    - Efforts to develop Affirmative Action Program 1965-1968 (Box 3)
    - Recruiting and testing non-whites for Michigan State Police 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Reports on Special Employment Programs 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous historical material (Box 3)
  - Booklets; "Rules of the Civil Service Commission (Box 3)
- Michigan Constitutional Convention
  - League of Women Votes: Campaign for Constitutional Revision 1958-1963, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Con-Con Organization, Powers and Procedures
    - Committee on Public Information (Box 3)
    - Organization and Procedures (Box 3)
    - Preparation for Con-Con (Box 3)
  - Civil Rights
    - Campaign for the adoption of the constitution 1962-1963 (Box 3)
    - Civil rights in the Constitutional Convention
      - General (Box 3)
      - Democrats pro and con statements (Box 3)
      - Constitutional implementation: Kelley opinion (Box 3)
      - Preparation of "Your Individual Rights in the New Constitution" research and correspondence (Box 3)
      - Harold Norris proposal for a Declaration of Rights in the constitution (Box 3)
  - Education Committee
    - Structure: finance (Box 4)
    - Universities: coordinated planning (Box 4)
  - Executive Branch
    - Administrative Board (Box 4)
    - Civil Service Department and Powers (Box 4)
    - Fiscal management (Box 4)
  - Judiciary
    - General (Box 4)
    - Family Court (Box 4)
    - Judicial Review of Administrative Tribunals (Box 4)
  - Legislative Branch
    - Eligibility of legislators to other offices (Box 4)
    - Pay (Box 4)
    - Powers, Auditor General (Box 4)
  - Reapportionment
    - Debate within Con-Con (Box 4)
    - Organization and citizen attitudes (Box 4)
    - Delegate Nord's views (Box 4)
    - Post Con-Con studies and opinions (Box 4)
    - Reapportionment-Michigan 1908-1952 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous provisions
    - Eminent domain (Box 4)
    - Internal improvements (Box 4)
  - Natural Resources
    - Clippings (Box 4)
    - Committee Consideration and Action (Box 4)
    - Dept. of Research & Drafting (Box 4)
    - Testimony & Letters (Box 4)
  - Finance and taxation
    - Property Taxes (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Metropolitan Problems; intergovernmental relations
    - Annexations and School Districts (Box 4)
    - Intergovernmental Relations, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - County Home Rule (Box 5)
    - Publications (Box 5)
    - History of, including League of Women Voters (Box 5)
    - 1963-1971 (Box 5)
    - Brake, Evolution of BBB Courthouse Gang Proposal (Box 5)
    - "The Great Compromise" (Box 5)
    - New York State (Box 5)
    - "Municipal Corporation Liberal Construction" (Box 5)
    - Documents in Progress (Box 5)
    - Hearings on Delegate Proposals on County (Box 5)
    - Variation in Michigan Counties (Box 5)
    - County Government, General (Box 5)
    - Local Government Committee, Action Journal, etc. (Box 5)
  - Implementing New Constitution
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Fiscal Management (Box 5)
    - Local Government (Box 5)
    - State & Metro Problems (Box 5)
    - Annexation & Incorporation (Box 5)
    - Civil Rights (Box 5)
    - Judiciary (Box 5)
    - Education (Box 5)
    - Apportionment (Box 5)
    - Taxes (Box 5)
  - Campaign for adoption of constitution
    - Clippings (Box 6)
    - Preservation of federalism (Box 6)
    - Letters to the editor (Box 6)
    - General speeches by other delegates (Box 6)
    - Individual Rights (Box 6)
    - Executive Branch, inc. highways (Box 6)
    - Fiscal Management and economic growth (Box 6)
    - Local Government Speech Notes (Box 6)
    - Speech notes, counter attack (Box 6)
    - Revision vs. Amendment (Box 6)
    - Does the new constitution fulfill the original purposes of revision? (Box 6)
    - Publicity-anti 1962-1963 (Box 6)
    - CIO Constitution (Box 6)
    - Highway lobby (Box 6)
    - Politics (inter-party) (Box 6)
    - Democrats, 1960-63 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks
    - League of Women Voters (Box 6)
  - Probate Court Jurisdiction over Juveniles (Box 6)
  - Journal of Michigan Constitutional Convention 1961 (diary of personal experiences) (photocopy) (Box 6)
  - Book chapter: "The Michigan League of Women Voters and the Campaign for State Constitutional Revision, 1958-1963" (photocopy) (Box 6)
  - Photographic slides of Constitutional Convention 1961-1962 (Box 6)
    (These slides were taken by Dorothy Judd; the descriptions are hers. The slides, formerly stored in 2 boxes, are now in slide sleeves. Each slide indicates the slide box and its number within the box.)
    - "ConCon takes root": spruce seedlings provided by the Michigan Landscape Association were favors at the banquet given for the delegates by the Constitutional Preparatory Commission June 1962 (Box 6)
      [1-1]
    - "Constitution Hall: a part of the Lansing Civic Center remodeled to accommodate the Convention." (Box 6)
      [1-2]
    - Constitution Hall. (Box 6)
      [1-3]
    - President Stephen S. Nisbet on the rostrum. (Box 6)
      (Judd comment: "A compromise candidate -- but one whom everyone trusted -- and came to love. Without such a man we might well have never achieved a new constitution.")
      [1-4]
    - Vice-President George Romney at his seat, Marjorie Frances McGowen and Edward Austin McLogan in front. (Box 6)
      [1-5]
    - Vice-President Tom Downs speaking from the floor. (Box 6)
      [1-6]
    - Vice-President Edward Hutchinson presiding, below is Secretary Fred I. Chase, Bernard Apol (Administrative Assistant to the President) and Bernice Tucker (Secretary to the President). (Box 6)
      [1-7]
    - The Convention celebrates Fred I. Chase's 40th wedding anniversary. (Box 6)
      [1-8]
    - The Press Gallery, Carl Rudow at desk of William Kulsea of the Detroit News (Box 6)
      [1-9]
    - ConCon goes on TV (Box 6)
      [1-10]
    - Visitors' Gallery. (Box 6)
      [1-11]
    - Special ConCon library provided by the State Library, Delegate Frank O. Staiger Jr. at work. (Box 6)
      [1-12]
    - Pages John Paul Dykstra, Jr.; L. Wayne Ferry; Kern Tomlin; Alan Johnston; Frederick Grasman (Box 6)
      [1-13]
    - Page Kern Tomlin gets a book for a delegate. (Box 6)
      [1-14]
    - The Kent County delegation with Nisbet and Chase: Left to right Paul Gordon Goebel; Ella Demnick Koeze; Walter Dale DeVries; Robert H. Blandford; Dorothy Leonard Judd; Robert Speer Tubbs; John Butlin Martin (Box 6)
      [1-15]
    - Delegate Paul Gordon Goebel, Grand Rapids (Box 6)
      [1-16]
    - Chairman Richard Campbell Van Dusen of the Committee on Rules and Regulations. (Box 6)
      [1-17]
    - Chairman John Hannah of the Committee on Legislative Organization. (Box 6)
      [1-18]
    - Chairman Martin of the Committee on the Executive Branch. (Box 6)
      [1-19]
    - Chairman John Danhof of the Committee on the Judicial Branch. (Box 6)
      [1-20]
    - Chairman D. Hale Brake of the Committee on Finance and Taxation (with wife). (Box 6)
      [1-21]
    - Chairman Arthur G. Elliott of the Committee on Local Government. (Box 6)
      [1-22]
    - Chairman Alvin M. Bentley of the Committee on Education. (Box 6)
      [1-23]
    - Chairman Frank G. Millard of the Committee on Emerging Problems. (Box 6)
      [1-24]
    - Chairman James K. Pollock of the Committee on Declaration of Rights, Suffrage and Election. (Box 6)
      [1-25]
    - Chairman William B. Cudlip of the Committee on Style and Drafting. (Box 6)
      [1-26]
    - Delegates John E. McCauley, Wyandotte; Paul Robert Mahinske, Detroit; Richard David Kuhn, Pontiac (Box 6)
      [1-27]
    - Delegates McGowan, McCauley. (Box 6)
      [1-28]
    - Delegate Raymond L. King, Pontiac (Box 6)
      [1-29]
    - Delegates Katherine Cushman and McLogan with President Nisbet. (Box 6)
      [1-30]
    - Delegates Nick James Rajkovitch, Traverse City; Roy C. Howes, Copemish (Box 6)
      [1-31]
    - Delegate William O. Green of Detroit debating "search and seizure" (Box 6)
      [1-32]
    - Party, McCauley speaking. (Box 6)
      [1-32a]
    - Delegate Charlie Follo and his bride give cause for celebration by members of the Local Government Committee and others. (Box 6)
      [1-33]
    - Delegate Elmer L. Radka, Rogers City presents a gift. (Box 6)
      [1-34]
    - "The guest of honor with Cushman and David Frederick Upton, St. Joseph." (Box 6)
      [1-35]
    - Delegate Cushman with her husband Ed at the Follo party. (Box 6)
      [1-36]
    - The Finches (Francis Finch) and the Radkas honor Follo. (Box 6)
      [1-37]
    - Chairman Danhof supporting his Judicial Branch proposals. (Box 6)
      [1-38]
    - Judge Tom Dehnke, vice-chairman of Committee on Legislative Organization. (Box 6)
      [1-39]
    - Judge Dehnke, vice-chairman of Committee on Legislative Organization. (Box 6)
      [1-40]
    - Committee on Legislative Organization works on apportionment, with John Hannah presiding. (Box 6)
      [2-1]
    - Delegate James K. Pollock. (Box 6)
      [2-2]
    - Delegate Weldon O. Yeager explains a proposed map. (Box 6)
      [2-3]
    - Two prominent CIO leaders and delegates: Robert G. Hodges, Detroit; William C. Marshall, Taylor (Box 6)
      [2-4]
    - "The hardest working committee in ConCon, thanks to John Hannah!" (Box 6)
      [2-5]
    - A proposed apportionment map. (Box 6)
      [2-6]
    - Another proposed apportionment map. (Box 6)
      [2-7]
    - "Proponents of County Home Rule conspire in Pollock's room" Left to right: Pollock, Follo, Joseph Don Lawrence, Judd, Cushman. (Box 6)
      [2-8]
    - Glenn Allen, Cushman. (Box 6)
      [2-9]
    - Follo, Tweedy, Allen, McCauley, Upton. (Box 6)
      [2-10]
    - McCauley, McLogan. (Box 6)
      [2-11]
    - "The 'Three BBBs' take over and kill constitutional County Home Rule": Brake (center), Peter L. Buback (left) and Martin W. Baginski. (Box 6)
      [2-12]
    - "Brake presents a consolation prize to the 'Young Radicals,' (the young liberal Republicans who favored County Home Rule": Left to right: King, DeVries, Clyne Ward Durst, not identified, Eugene Wanger. (Box 6)
      [2-13]
    - Wanger, Hazen van den Berg Hatch, McLogan, Upton, Tweedie. (Box 6)
      [2-14]
    - "ConCon burns the midnight oil" (Box 6)
      [2-15]
    - Local Government Committee celebrates when their work is done (Follo, Allen, Cushman) (Box 6)
      [2-16]
    - Julius Charles Sleder, Cushman, McCauley. (Box 6)
      [2-17]
    - McCauley, Tweedie, Judd, McLogan. (Box 6)
      [2-18]
    - McLogan, Judd, Baginski, Finch. (Box 6)
      [2-19]
    - The Finches and the Radkas. (Box 6)
      [2-20]
    - The Tweedies (Sanfor Martin Tweedie III, Port Huron) (Box 6)
      [2-21]
    - George Thomas Sharpe III, Finch, not identified, Elliott. (Box 6)
      [2-22]
    - The Farnsworths. (James S. Farnsworth, Allegan) (Box 6)
      [2-23]
    - Baginski and Buback. (Box 6)
      [2-24]
    - Charles Figy and Allen. (Box 6)
      [2-25]
    - Committee on Style and drafting prepares the proposed constitution for 3rd reading. (Box 6)
      [2-26]
    - May 11. "Father Malcolm Dade invokes God's help" (Box 6)
      [2-27]
    - May 11. "The delegates watch the red and green lights flash for the third reading of the whole constitution." (Box 6)
      [2-28]
    - May 11. "The big board tells the story." (Box 6)
      [2-29]
    - May 11. Count the votes: Yeas 99, Nays 44, 1 abstaining. (Box 6)
      [2-30]
    - Committee on Public Information writes the "Address to the People." Chairman Ink White second from left. (Box 6)
      [2-31]
    - "The News Media reports the big news!" (Box 6)
      [2-32]
    - "The delegates are off and running -- for the next election, November, 1962." (Box 6)
      [2-33]
    - "And the ConCon spruces keep on growing." (Box 6)
      [2-34]
    - "Postscript: The ConCon spruces are hale and hearty still in 1975." (Box 6)
      [2-35]
    - Steno pool. (Box 6)
      [2-36]
    - 1960 population by county. (Box 6)
      [2-37]
    - 1970 population by county with per cent and totals. (Box 6)
      [2-38]
    - County per cent population 1960. (Box 6)
      [2-39]
    - Senate and House concentric zones (Box 6)
      [2-40]
    - Social-economic geographic areas, William Hanna plan. Senate-House. (Box 6)
      [2-41]
    - House -- 110 "straight pop" with county lines. (Box 6)
      [2-42]
    - House -- 110-.7 1960 County lines, equal proportions. (Box 6)
      [2-43]
    - House Minority -- 115 Report. On county lines. (Box 6)
      [2-44]
    - House Chart per cent plans. (Box 6)
      [2-45]
    - Per cent House plans. (Box 6)
      [2-46]
    - Pollack Senate plan (Box 6)
      [2-47]
    - Romney Senate apportionment plan (Box 6)
      [2-48]
    - House 110-.7 Apportionment Committee Map. (Box 6)
      [2-49]
    - Bill Hanna, McCauley. (Box 6)
      [2-50]
    - Land area -- county percentages. (Box 6)
      [2-51]
    - League of Women Voters, plan II, Senate. (Box 6)
      [2-52]
    - Senate minority report on county lines. (Box 6)
      [2-53]
    - Present Senate 1952 Amendment. (Box 6)
      [2-54]
    - League of Women Voters no. I, Senate. (Box 6)
      [2-55]
    - 1970 population, Senate, 40 seats. (Box 6)
      [2-56]
    - Faxon -- Senate, using county lines. (Box 6)
      [2-57]
    - Present House districts -- Detroit. (Box 6)
      [2-58]
    - Senate chart. (Box 6)
      [2-59]
    - Wm. Hanna [plan] Senate 1970 39 [Senators], 80-20 per cent. (Box 6)
      [2-60]
    - House -- 101 1960 population, no moiety, using county lines. (Box 6)
      [2-61]
    - House districts, Kent County, now, with some annotations. (Box 6)
      [2-62]
    - House districts, Kent County before annexations (Box 6)
      [2-63]
    - Grand Rapids annexations. (Box 6)
      [2-64]
    - House -- 50 per cent moiety. (Box 6)
      [2-65]
- Kent County Airport Site Planning
  - Federal hearing (Box 6)
  - West Michigan Regional Airport Development Committee
    - Membership and Minutes (Box 6)
    - Advisory reports, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Documents (Box 6)
  - Arguments pro and con (Box 6)
  - Kent County Airport, first annual report 1957 (Box 6)
  - Working papers (Box 6)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 6)
- Grand Rapids Politics and Reform
  - Paper: "Spoils Politics In Michigan and in Grand Rapids 1870-1970" by Dorothy Leonard Judd (Box 6)
  - Political history of Grand Rapids City government 1912-1952 (Box 6)
  - Arthur H. Vandenberg letters and miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Recall campaign against May or George Welsh 1949
    - Event leading up to campaign (Box 7)
    - Firing of city manager Frank Goebel May 1949 (Box 7)
    - Fulton Park rally May 1949 (Box 7)
    - Validity of recall petitions (Box 7)
    - Recall of commissioner Carl Richards (Box 7)
    - Correspondence with professor Paul Ylvisaker of Swarthmore College concerning the recall campaign (Box 7)
    - DLJ assessment of recall (Box 7)
    - George Welsh libel suit against Dorothy Judd 1963-1968 (Box 7)
    - Original materials from the recall movement and its aftermath (Box 7)
      (formerly maintained as a scrapbook)
  - Citizens Action 1949-1955
    - Minute book 1949-1952 (Box 7)
    - Citizen Action movement and the reform cycle (Box 7)
    - Citizens Action origin (Box 7)